Anderson Piffer

Product Manager & Game Designer

+55 11 99254-0970 4piffer@gmail.com Skype: a.piffer

COVER LETTER

I'm a product manager and game designer specialized in F2P mobile games with 30+ games published on App Store and Google Play. Since 2016 I've been leading teams from 3 to 23 amazing people into creating fun and profitable games through goal oriented, iterative, collaborative and data-informed processes. From 2011-2015 I've designed dozens of games with different genres and audiences which some become top-downloaded games around the world. It's worth mention that games are my passion since childhood and I truly believe I can help the world become a better place through games (seriously!).

You may check out more about my best projects at http://apiffer.com.

KEY SKILLS

- Creating engaging mobile games that drives great retention and monetization metrics
- · Leading multidisciplinary teams and collaborating with people from different backgrounds
- · Analyzing the market, players' feedback and KPIs in order to plan and prioritize strategies

TECHNICAL

- · Communication: Docs, Spreadsheets, Slides (Google) / Word, Excel, PowerPoint (Microsoft)
- Software management: JIRA, Confluence, Trello.
- Product analytics: Firebase, Data Studio, Tableau.
- Game design and development: Spreadsheets, Unity3D, Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya.
- Programming languages (basic skills): C#, LUA, HTML.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager, Tapps Games, January 2016 – Today

- Managing successful mobile games such as My Boo, which is played by millions per day and became the most important Tapps game in terms of revenue
- Defining and driving the product vision, roadmap and backlog to stakeholders and the team
- Collaborating with analysts and production leadership to execute product initiatives
- Leading multidisciplinary teams using agile methodologies
- Analyzing the market, users' feedback, and metrics in order to discover opportunities, prioritize and implement changes or A/B tests that ultimately lead to high commercial impact through better KPIs

Game Designer, Tapps Games, July 2013 - December 2015

- Designed, documented and balanced core-loops, systems, levels, and virtual economies for successful freemium mobile games on App Store and Google Play (E.g.: My Boo, Cow Evolution)
- Communicated and collaborated with game designers, developers, artists, sound designers, business and marketing analysts during the whole game and updates production cycles
- Analyzed retention, engagement and monetization metrics, games analytics data, best-practices and user feedback in order to design new updates and plan A/B tests

UI/UX Designer, eFlow Games (independent studio), August 2012 - January 2013

- Designed and documented all interfaces: wireframes, user flow, mock-ups, prototypes
- Organized playtests and iterated with user feedback to improve our designs
- Created 2D UI art assets including HUD, Menus, feedback and particles

Design Intern, Tapps, August 2011 - August 2012

- Pitched, designed, documented, and balanced new game mechanics for mobile platforms
- Created fun and engaging levels using in-house tools
- Defined monetization systems and in-game economies (freemium business model)
- Assisted Quality Assurance and Art teams in some projects

EDUCATION

Immersive Program in Creative Leadership, Polifonia, 2018

Professional Education in Product Management, Cursos PM3, 2018

Bachelor's Degree in Game Design, Universidade Anhembi Morumbi (UAM), 2009 - 2012

- Created several games from conception to a playable demo, acting in different roles and in groups
- Published an undergraduate research on Cognitive Usability (UX Design for Games)
- Final thesis focusing on Resource Management and Strategy in Game Design

Drawing and Art Study, Pacearte Studio, 2008 - 2011

LANGUAGES

Brazilian Portuguese: Native
English: Fluent